お前が死ぬ
β世界線に戻れば
あのＤメールを消せば
If we return to the beta world line...
If we undo that first D-mail...
Being Meltdown
You will die.
ここだったか
So, there you are.
こんな所で寝ていると
熱中症になるぞ
If you keep lying there, you'll get heatstroke.
あんただって ラボの屋上で
寝っ転がってたでしょ
You sleep on the roof of the lab
all the time, don't you?
それに 今は曇ってる
Besides, it's cloudy now.
まゆりには会えたの？
Did you see Mayuri?
橋田が コミマでは
会えなかったみたいって
Hashida said he couldn't find her at Comima...
ああ その後 会えた
Yeah.
I met up with her after that.
そう
I see.
ねえ 岡部
Hey, Okabe...
何だ？
What?
うん？
分かった
All right.
うん？
おい… 雨だぞ
Hey.
うん？ あっ！
It's raining.
うわあ～！
ああっ！
なんぞ これ～！
WTF?!
はあ はあ…
もう少し 早く忠告してよ
Why didn't you warn me earlier?
おかげで 下着まで
びしょぬれじゃない もう…
I'm soaked, down to my underwear...
ちゃんと 声は かけた
I did tell you.
聞いていなかったのは
クリスティーナの…
It's your fault, Christina, for not listen—
おっ…
えっ？
なっ… このHENTAI！
Y-You pervert!
別に 見ようと思って
見たわけではないぞ！
I wasn't trying to look...
貴様が そんな透けやすい服を
着ているのが…
And it's your fault for wearing such thin clothes.
あんたが HENTAIだってこと
忘れてたわ
I'd forgotten you were such a pervert.
お前の貧相なヌードなど
見るに値するとでも…
Who'd want to see your stick figure in the nude...
それ以上 言ったら
あんたの大脳新皮質を
One more word, and I turn
your neocortex into a flower pot!
ポン酢漬けにしてやるから！
どういう脅し…
近づかないで！
What kind of threat is that?
Stay away from me!
って 何それ？
What's that?
うん？ あっ…
お前を捜している時
どこかに引っかけたか…
I got scratched somewhere,
when I was looking for you...
フッ… ドジっ子
Klutz!
俺の属性は
マッドサイエンティストであり…
I'm classified as a "mad scientist"...
はいはい
まったく 世話が焼けるわね
Right, right!
You're so much trouble...
貸して ちょうど
ソーイングセットがあるから
Hand that over.
I have a sewing kit on me.
縫ってあげる
I'll fix it up.
ソーイングセット？
A sewing kit?
これでも 相対的に見れば
家庭的なほうなのよ
I consider myself more family-oriented
than most people.
ほら 脱いで
Take it off.
先に言っておくけど
Just to be clear,
この暗さだから
出来については期待しないこと
it's dark, so don't expect too much.
あと 糸が何色になるか
出てからの お楽しみね
And you can look forward to finding out,
after we leave, what color thread I used.
黒 赤 ピンク 確率は３分の１
Black, red, pink...
You have a 33% chance of each one.
はあ…
ピンクが出ないよう 祈ろう
I'll just pray it isn't pink.
ちょ… 来ないでよ
Stay back.
安心しろ
お前の貧相なヌードに興味など…
Don't worry.
I'm not interested in that stick figure of yours...
ポン酢漬けにするって
言ってんだろ
I told you... A flower pot!
はあ… まったく…
Jeez...
どこをぶらついたら
こんな所 破けるのよ
Where did you have to go,
to rip your clothes like this?
今日は ラボに行って
Today, I went to the lab,
ランドリー 散歩
the laundry,
a walk.
それから
お前が泊まっているホテル
And then to your hotel.
ホテル？ 行ったの？
The hotel? You stopped by?
お前のせいだぞ
It's your fault.
メールの返信は よこさない
電話にも出ない
You wouldn't answer my messages.
You weren't picking up your phone.
まさか 心配してくれ…
Were you worried about me...
助手の管理は ラボのあるじである
俺の仕事だからな
As head of the lab,
it's my job to keep track of my assistant.
アハッ…
まだ できないのか？
It isn't done yet?
ちょっと待って
うん？
Almost...
ほれ！
うわっ… あっ 冷たっ！ お前！
Here!
That's cold. Hey!
早く着なさい
Just put it on.
I'm not interested in the stick figure
of a nude mad scientist.
マッドサイエンティストの
貧相なヌードなど
興味ないのだからな
ワ～ッハッハッハ！
ああ ハッ…
多分 この近くよね
うん？
It was probably around here, right?
私が… 刺された場所
The place I was stabbed...
なっ… どうして それを？
How did you know?
やっぱり 夢にしては
The pain and despair were too real for a dream.
痛さや絶望感が
あまりにリアルだったから
紅莉栖 まさか お前…
Kurisu. You can't mean...
うん 私の中にもね
I have hazy memories inside.
ぼんやりと記憶があるの
淡い まるで 幻みたいな記憶
Weak, almost nonexistent memories...
刺された時のことだけじゃない
Not just of being stabbed.
岡部のことも ぼんやりと覚えてる
I remember you, too... hazily...
まゆりを助けようと必死になって
How desperate you were to save Mayuri.
一人で傷つきながらも
前に進もうとしているの
How you kept pressing forward,
even hurt and all alone.
決して 元の世界には戻せないのに
You haven't made it back to your original world,
それでも 必死に あらがって
but you've kept going,
まゆりの名前を必死で叫んで
涙を流して
kept calling her name,
kept crying...
ひたむきに助けようとしている
岡部がいるの
Kept trying to save her.
その顔を見る度に 私は思うの
Every time I see that face,
I think about how important she is to you...
岡部にとって どれだけ
まゆりが かけがえのない存在か
And about whether it's possible for someone
誰かが誰かを
ここまで大切に思えるのかって
to truly care for another person that much...
だから 私は 岡部に協力したい
That's why I wanted to work with you.
岡部の手助けをしたいと思った
That's why I wanted to help you.
ねえ 岡部 まゆりを助けて
Okabe, save Mayuri.
岡部は
まゆりを助けるべきなのよ！
You must save her.
お前は どうなる？
If we go to the beta world line, you'll die!
β世界線に行ったら 死ぬんだぞ！
でも そうするしかないの
But it's the only way...
あんたが
一番 よく分かってるでしょ？
You know that better than anyone, right?
選択肢は １つしかない
There's only one option.
お前を… 見捨てろっていうのか？
You!
You're telling me to abandon you?
他に方法がある？
Is there another way?
昨日から何度も考えた
I've been thinking about the following since yesterday...
今までみたいに 何か打つ手が…
"Isn't there some other way?"
何か方法があるんじゃないかって
"Isn't there something else we can do?"
でも 無理
But this time, I can't come up with anything...
今度ばかりは どうしようもない
Except going to the beta world line.
β世界線に行くしか方法はないの
岡部！
Okabe!
こんなの… 俺は認めない
I refuse to accept this...
諦めない！
I won't give up!
できるわけないだろ
紅莉栖を見捨てるなんて…
I can't...
I can't abandon Kurisu.
あいつを見殺しにして
生きていくなんて…
I can't let her die and then keep living.
そんなことに 何の意味がある？
What would the point of that be?
俺は… 俺は…
I...
うっ…！
あっ… はっ！
はあ はあ はあ…
逃げたって…
You can run away...
You can run away, but that'll just make it worse!
逃げたって 苦しくなるだけよ！
うるさい！
Shut up!
何度 タイムリープしたって
１％の壁は越えられない！
No matter how many times you time leap,
you can't get past the 1% barrier!
やってみなきゃ分からないだろ！
We don't know until we try!
まゆりが死ぬところを
見るだけなのよ？ 何回も…
You'll just see Mayuri die!
Again...
そんなの 岡部が壊れちゃう
It'll destroy you.
It won't...
壊れなど… しない
俺が 何回
まゆりの死を見てきたと思ってる
How many times do you think I've watched her die?
何回も見てきた
I've seen it again...
何回も 何回も 何回も 何回も…
And again and again and again
and again and again...
もう そんなもので
心が壊れたりしない
It won't destroy me...
The number of times I see it doesn't matter!
何度 繰り返そうが同じ！
自分が
何 言ってるか 分かってる？
Do you hear what you're saying?
まゆりが 苦しんで死んでいくのよ
Mayuri's going to suffer and die...
｢そんなもの｣なわけないじゃない
How can you say it doesn't matter?
それで 岡部の心が
動かないんだとしたら
If that doesn't affect you,
もう 岡部の心は壊れている…
then your heart's already broken...
もう やめて
Just stop...
本当に壊れちゃうよ…
Or it really will break you.
I know.
分かってる 気付いてた
I noticed it long ago.
まゆりが何度も死んでいるのに
俺は驚かなくなっていた
No matter how many times Mayuri died,
I stopped being surprised.
いつの間にか 心がマヒしていた
I'd gone numb without even knowing it.
まゆりが死ぬ時刻を確かめようと
Sometimes, I even waited before time leaping,
just to see when she'd die.
タイムリープせずに
待っていたことすらあった
まゆりが死ぬのに
At some point,
it just stopped affecting me.
俺の心は
いつからか動かなくなって…
冷静に やり直せばいいって
Somewhere inside, I was calmly telling myself
that I could do it over...
どこかで そう思ってた
まゆりを助けて
Save her...
そうしないと
本当に 岡部が壊れてしまう
If you don't, it will destroy you.
まゆりを見殺しになんかしたら
絶対に後悔する！
If you let her die, you'll regret it... I'm certain!
まゆりを助けようっていう
思いだけで
You and I have come this far,
from the single wish to save her!
岡部と私は ここまで来た
ここで やめたら
一生 後悔し続ける
If we stop, we'll always regret it.
でも まゆりを助けたら お前は…
But if we save her...
You'll...
戻るだけよ！
I'll just go back!
To the first world line, before the D-mail was sent!
Ｄメールが送られなかった
最初の世界線に
それが 私のためであり
岡部のためでもある！
That's what's best for me...
And it's what's best for you!
あっ…
How many times have we fought,
over these past twenty days?
この20日間 何度も衝突した
互いに 憎まれ口をたたき合った
We've made fun of each other.
相談し合ったりもした
We've talked about our problems.
When my back was against the wall,
I turned to Kurisu.
追い詰められた俺が
助けを求めたのは 紅莉栖だった
俺の話を黙って聞き
信じてくれたのは 紅莉栖だった
Kurisu was the one who listened to me,
who believed me...
18歳で学術誌に論文が載った
天才少女は
At eighteen, a genius with a
published academic paper.
常に 冷静で 強がりで
プライドが高くて おせっかいで
Always calm, always strong-willed.
Always so proud and nosy.
根は 真面目すぎるほど真面目で
But always so kind and honest.
俺は いつだって
彼女の語る理論にしびれて
Her theories continually amazed me.
彼女の言葉を胸に刻み込んで
And I remembered everything she said.
彼女の動きを目で追っていた
Watched everything she did...
単なる仲間じゃない
She wasn't just another lab member.
俺とって 牧瀬 紅莉栖は…
To me, Makise Kurisu was...
俺は…
I can't save you...
お前を助けられない
I'm sorry.
すまない
ありがとう
Thank you.
私のために
そこまで苦しんでくれて…
For suffering so much for me...
なんで お前なんだって…
Why was it you?
Why you?!
どうして お前なんだって…
ねえ 世界線が変わるって
どういうことなんだろう？
Hey, what does it mean to change world lines?
もしかしたら
岡部が β世界線に行った瞬間
Maybe the second you go to the beta world line,
この世界から 岡部という存在が
消えるだけかもしれない
you'll just disappear from this world.
別の岡部という存在に
変わるのかもしれない
Or maybe you trade places with another Okabe.
そんなの… 意味がない
That doesn't matter...
そんなことない 私は死んでない
That's not true.
I'm not dead.
Even if I'm dead in the beta world line,
β世界線の私が
死んでいたとしても
there's no guarantee that I'm going to die here!
今 ここにいる私が死ぬ保証は
どこにもない
無数の世界線に
別の私がいるかもしれない
There could be another me,
amidst all the other, infinite world lines.
その意思が つながって
And our minds are connected and comprise "me."
自分という存在が
あるのかもしれない
それって… ステキだと思わない？
Don't you think that'd be wonderful?
You'd be everywhere, in every time, at once.
あらゆる時 あらゆる場所に
自分がいる
誰かを愛する強い気持ちが
A great love for someone,
何かを信じる強い感情が
a great belief in something,
a great desire to pass on something...
何かを伝えたいという強い思いが
時を超え つながって
今の自分があるのだとしたら
If all those things surpass time itself and create "you,"
それは すばらしいこと
wouldn't that be wonderful?
So don't think of it as abandoning me.
だから
見殺しにするなんて思わないで
世界線が変わっても
たった一人 岡部が忘れなければ
Even if the world line changes,
as long as you don't forget me, I'm there.
私は そこにいる
だから…
So...
お前のことは 絶対に忘れない
I will never forget you.
I won't forget the person I care for most.
誰よりも大切な人のことを
忘れたりしない
それって…
Does that mean...
It's the truth.
事実だ
H-How... It's so sudden...
そんなこと なんで 急に…
俺は お前が好きだ
I'm in love with you.
はっ？
What about you?
お前は どうなんだ？
と 言いますと？
What do you mean?
聞いておきたいんだ
I want to hear your response.
お前は 俺のことを
どう思ってる？
How do you feel about me?
知りたいのか？
ああ
You want to know?
Yeah.
顔を… 目を閉じろ
Your face... Close your eyes.
Why?
どうして？
いいから 閉じなさいよ
Just do it!
べ 別に
したくてしたわけじゃないから
I-I didn't want to do that, okay?
ただ ファーストキスのような
強烈な行為と共に
But experiences, such as your first kiss,
海馬に記憶されたエピソードは
忘却されにくいのよ だから…
that are stored in the hippocampus with your
strong memories are harder to forget.
So...
残念だったな
Too bad.
俺は
これが ファーストキスではない
That wasn't my first kiss.
な 生意気な童貞のくせに！
You bratty virgin!
うるさい 処女
Shut up, virgin.
もっとも ファーストキスは
My first kiss wasn't at all romantic.
ロマンチックなものでは
なかったがな
とにかく
今のは 印象としては弱い
Anyway...
That last one only left a weak impression.
もう一度だ
えっ？ あっ…
Once more.
I don't want to forget, not ever.
絶対に忘れたくないから
念には念を入れる いいな？
So I'll take extra care.
それなら しょうがないな…
Well, I guess that's okay.
Just a kiss, right?
キスだけだぞ
時間が
あっという間に流れていく
Time is passing so quickly...
今だけは アインシュタインに
文句を言いたい気分
Right now, I feel like complaining to Einstein.
ねえ 岡部
You know, Okabe...
Whether time is slow or fast
時間は 人の意識によって
長くなったり短くなったりする
depends on perception.
Relativity theory is so romantic.
相対性理論って
とてもロマンチックで
とても切ないものだね
And so sad.
それじゃあ
Goodbye, then.
Sure about not saying it to Mayuri and Daru?
まゆりとダルは
本当に いいのか？
Everyone seeing me off would just make it worse.
みんなに見送られると
つらくなるから
If it's only you,
岡部だけなら
何のためらいもなく日本をたてる
I can leave Japan without any hesitation.
ジョークよ
That was a joke.
手土産だ 受け取れ
It's a present.
Take it.
うっ… ああ…
いらねえ…
I don't want this...
I upgraded it to version 2.67.
バージョン2.67に
アップデートしてある
What a pain.
ややこしいわね
でも まあ 受け取っておく
But I'll take it anyway.
じゃあ
Bye.
紅莉栖！
そうだ
Kurisu!
Right...
お返し！ ふっ！
This is for you!
あっ！ あっ…
Where were you throwing that?
どこに投げている
ちゃんと受け取れ！
Go get it.
ったく…
Jeez...
あっ…
Okabe...
岡部
I'm sure, whatever happens, you're going to suffer.
これから きっと
岡部は つらい思いをする
Only you will remember me,
私のことを
誰も覚えていない世界で
in a world where no one else does.
ただ一人 私を覚えているなんて…
仲間を
なにより大事にする岡部には
More than anyone else, you care for your friends,
so that'll be painful for you.
つらいことだと思う
ごめんね
I'm sorry.
でも 私には
そのつらさが いとおしい
But somehow, I'm glad you'll have that pain.
ラボにいる何気ない時間
Those times when you're sitting around the lab...
When you drink a can of juice...
ジュースを口にした時
街を歩く その一瞬
When you walk around town...
いつか 誰かとキスした時
And someday, when you kiss someone.
いつもじゃなくてもいい
100回に１回でもいい
It doesn't have to be every time...
It can be one time out of a hundred...
私を思い出してほしい
But I'd like you to remember me.
そこに 私はいるから
Because I'll be there...
１％の壁の向こうに
私は 必ず いるから
I'll be there, beyond the 1% barrier!
岡部 岡部…
Okabe...
Okabe.
Okabe!
岡部…
Oh, man.
おっと！ オカリン 見つけた！
Okarin, I found it.
マジで あったぞ これっしょ！
This is it...
This is totally it!
If we delete this...
これを消せば…
Mission complete.
ミッション コンプリート？
Okarin,
オカリン 大丈夫？
are you okay?
大丈夫だ
I'm fine...
これより 現在を司る女神作戦
最終フェイズを開始する！
We now begin the final phase of Operation Verdandi!
Our victory is nigh!
勝利の時は来た！
We have overcome all conspiracies...
あらゆる陰謀に屈せず 己の…
己の信念を貫き
Upholding our ideals to the last.
And finally, we have fought through
the battle of Ragnarok!
我々は ついに
ラグナロックを戦い抜いたのだ！
この勝利のために
I thank those who have worked so hard for me,
我が手足となって戦ってくれた
仲間たちに感謝を！
to ensure this victory!
I am grateful to all those I have had to sacrifice...
犠牲となった すべての思いに
感謝を…
訪れるのは 俺が望んだ世界であり
What comes now is the world I wished for!
This is all the choice of Steins Gate!
全ては 運命石の扉の選択である！
世界は…
The world...
再構築される！
...will be rebuilt!
Kurisu...
紅莉栖…
I'm sorry.
すまない…
Okabe!
岡部！
うん？
はあ はあ はあ…
岡部 私も…
Okabe...
I'm also...
紅莉栖！
Kurisu!
I'm also in...
私も 岡部のことが…
あっ！
Mayuri?
まゆり
うん？
Who is Lab Member 004?
ラボメンNo.004は誰だ？
004?
004？ う～ん…
There isn't an 004.
004の人はいないよ
フッ… フフフ…
Now the battle of Ragnarok has ended!
今 ここに
ラグナロックの勝敗は決した！
I, the mad scientist, Hououin Kyouma,
have controlled time itself,
この俺 狂気の
マッドサイエンティストである
鳳凰院 凶真は
foiling the Organization and SERN's schemes,
機関 および
ＳＥＲＮのあらゆる攻撃に対し
and bringing about complete victory!
時空を操ることで
完全に勝利したのだ！
世界の支配構造はリセットされ
混沌の未来が待つであろう
The world's ruling structure has been reset!
And a future of chaos awaits!
This is the choice of Steins Gate!
これこそが 運命石の扉の選択！
Okarin, it's all right.
オカリン もういいんだよ
What are you saying?
何を？
俺は 今 華麗なる勝利宣言を…
I've just issued a declaration of victory...
もう その口調を
続けなくてもいいんだよ
You don't have to talk like that anymore.
まゆしぃは もう大丈夫だから
Mayushii is okay now.
So you can cry for yourself, Okarin.
オカリンは オカリンのために
泣いてもいいんだよ
We no longer need the Phone Microwave.
電話レンジは もう要らない
このマシンがあったことで
紅莉栖と出会えた
Because of it, I met Kurisu.
けれど このマシンがあったことで
But because of it, so many were hurt...
たくさんの人が傷ついた
鳳凰院 凶真が死んだように
Just as Hououin Kyouma has died,
the Phone Microwave should die, as well.
電話レンジも また
死ぬべきなのだ
生きることは 本来
やり直しが利かないことだから
Living should mean no do-overs...
これで いいんだ
This is for the best. Right, Kurisu?
そうだよな？ 紅莉栖…
は～い
Hello?
Huh? Wh-Who's this?
えっ？
だ 誰？
Dad?
父さん？ 何？ オカリン？
What?
Okarin?
Okarin, there's a mysterious girl
who wants to talk to you!
オカリン 謎の女が代われってさ！
誰だ？
Who is this?
Please come to the Radio Building's roof immediately!
お願い！
今すぐ ラジ館屋上に来て！
ああ？ お前は？
Who are you?
I've come from the year 2036.
あたしは 2036年から来た
橋田 至の娘 阿万音 鈴羽！
I'm Hashida Itaru's daughter, Amane Suzuha!
Suzuha?
鈴羽…？ ちょっと待て！
鈴羽が なんで ここにいるんだ？
Wait!
What are you doing here?
Please believe what I'm about to tell you.
お願い あたしの言うことを信じて
You must stop World War III.
第三次世界大戦を防ぐために
はっ…！
理美さんの友人の
古葉詩織と申します
あの 理美は今 ちょ…
弁護士をしております
今日は
理美さんの友人としてではなく
代理人として来ました
代理人…
チューリップです
公園 通過
単刀直入に申し上げます
悠斗君を理美さんに
引き渡していただきたいんです